is actually a puzzle right and and most
people I think when they approach the
book of Revelation because the book
appears to be so scattered they never
think to actually put together the
puzzle and what we're going to see that
the book of Revelation is actually like
a perfect puzzle okay so everything fits
together in a beautiful pattern so
that's what we'll see as well the book
of Revelation actually brings all the
other books of the Bible together into
one one book right so in a certain sense
the more familiar you are with the other
books of the Bible is the more likely
you'll be able to understand the book of
Revelation and again you don't need to
worry here because guess what the book
of the Bible itself is a book of
pictures right so when you get to the
book of Revelation all you're really
doing is you're taking the pictures from
the other portions of Scripture and you
are you are comparing those pictures
with the book of Revelation right you're
matching pictures again it's what I call
total theology let's begin with this now
if you have pen and paper I would
suggest just think of this as a class
right now okay
and we're going to my job is to try to
simplify the book of Revelation for you
so that you will be able to understand
it much much easier
what I'm doing here is I'm not only
trying to help you to understand but I
believe that God wants us to be able to
teach this book right so it's one thing
to be able to understand it it's another
thing to understand it well enough to
teach it and this is kind of what I'm
introducing some of you here too okay so
let's begin
enough with the preliminaries let's go
ahead and jump in and here's the first
thing I want you to do first thing we
need to do is we need to step back and
see the big picture or rather just
understand what is in the book of
Revelation right so I'm gonna call the
I want to see if you can if you can
follow along with me and even give me
the answers before getting to you all
right so we're just going to go through
the chapters and I want you to try to
see if you can figure out or if you know
what's in these chapters so Revelation
chapter 1 what would be in Revelation
chapter 1 when you see if you can put
your answers up on the screen how atonte
it's good to see you on here otama thing
is somewhere else right now so hi man of
ok Revelation chapter 1 is basically the
introduction John the Revelator is
coming is having this vision of Jesus
and he's on the Isle of Patmos and Jesus
is about to tell him that he's about to
give him letters to seven churches all
right so that's Revelation chapter 1 in
Revelation chapter 2 Revelation chapter
2 what's in revelation chapter 2 is an
introduction to the seven churches so
you got Ephesus Smyrna Pergamum Thyatira
in Revelation chapter 3 they have a
continuation of the churches Sardis
Philadelphia and Laodicea
so that's Revelation chapter 1 chapter 2
chapter 3 seven churches okay so if you
were to summarize the first three
chapters of Revelation it's the seven
churches from chapter 4 and chapter in
chapter 4 and chapter 5 you have an
introductory revision to the seven seals
and then from chapter five six seven
into eight you have a seven seals so
let's recap revelation one two three
seven churches
revelation four through eight seven
seals
very good okay I'm seeing the answer is
not very good Revelation chapter eight
begins the trumpets
so one through three seven churches four
through eight
seven seals and then eight picks up with
the seven trumpets and the Seven
trumpets take us all the way through
Revelation chapter chapter 11
alright so seven trumpets go from
Revelation chapter eight to Revelation
chapter 11 now
Revelation chapter 12 is Satan and his
angels warring against Michael
Revelation chapter 13 is you have the
introduction of the beasts from the
earth and the beasts from the sea
Revelation chapter 14 you have the three
angels messages and the 144,000 okay so
if we were to group these chapters we
would say chapters one through three
seven churches chapters four through
eight seven seals and chapter eight
through eleven seven trumpets chapter
twelve thirteen and fourteen we might
call the great controversy theme right
chapter 12 13 14 the great controversy
theme chapters 15 is where the plagues
begin so fifteen sixteen are the place
17 18 and 19 are the fall of Babylon
chapter 20 is the Millennium and chapter
21 and 22 is happily ever after
alright you understand the tree in the
context of the forest if you will so
that's why I'm doing it this way as I'm
giving you a big picture of the entire
book of Revelation right okay so
hopefully that helps all right so once
again let's let's look at this right
you've got chapters one through three
seven churches chapters four through
eight seven seals chapter eight through
eleven seven trumpets chapter twelve
thirteen and fourteen great controversy
theme from 15 and 16 we have the seven
last plagues seventeen
2:19 the fall of Babylon 20 the
millennium 21 and 22 let's just call it
happily ever after okay now with that in
mind we're going to we're going to we're
going to put the book of Revelation in a
different context to kind of help you
see the big picture okay so here's what
we gonna do I want you to notice that in
Revelation chapter 1 verse 20 and if you
have your Bibles you can open up and
look there but in Revelation chapter 1
verse 20 here is what the Bible says
this is really very interesting
revelation 1 verse 20 the mystery of the
Seven Stars which thou sawest in my
right hand and the Seven golden
candlesticks the seven stars are the
angels of the seven churches and the
seven candlesticks which thou sawest are
the seven churches you go to chapter 2
verse 1 on to the Angel of the Church of
Laodicea okay now that's very
interesting right because the messages
to the seven churches are directed to
angels that's really really very
interesting now you know in the actual
context these angels are going to
represent the leaders you know of the
church whatever church age we're looking
at right whether it's Ephesus or Smyrna
or what happened however here's what I
want you to see good evening sister
welcome here's what I want you to see
the the seven churches let me see
someone can give me the answer to this
what are the seven churches what is
Jesus doing in relation to the seven
churches like what is his message to the
seven churches to repent very good
repent the message to the seven churches
is about repentance okay very good
the message of the seven seals right and
again we're just kind of running through
this quickly but you're not going to get
lost so just follow along the message of
the seven seals is really about the
progress
of evil okay so he's first started with
a rider on a white horse which
represents Jesus but then after that you
have a rider on a red horse around it on
a black horse around around a pale horse
and you have this this storyline of this
progression of evil right the red horse
has taken away peace from the earth the
black horse is compromised the pale
horse is death in hell and then trumpets
five and six are going to deal with with
the Saints being persecuted then and
then the earth you know kind of like
it's cut it's chaos right ends up in
chaos but the message of the seven seals
is basically the progression of evil all
right so the message of the seven
churches is what repent the message of
the seven seals is progression of evil
it's the story of the progression of
evil the message of the seven trumpets
or the theme of the seven trumpet is
really about more right the trumpets
symbolize war in the Old Testament so
you're not only getting blew the
trumpets you remember when they marched
around Jericho and blew the trumpets God
talked about you know when a trumpet was
blown you know sounding a trumpet it was
a battle cry if you will so the seven
trumpets represent war okay now the the
revelation 12 13 and 14 the great
controversy theme is really about the
warning of the three angels messages
right so listen that let's recount very
quickly seven churches repent seven
seals the progression of evil seven
trumpets war revelation 12 13 and 14
three angels messages revelation 15 16
17 18 and 19 all talk about the
punishment of the wiki right so 15 and
16 the plagues 17 18 19 the fall of
Babylon
and in Revelation 20 Satan is cast out
revelation 21 and 22 everything is good
happily ever after right all right now
check this out because this is this is
really amazing you need to see this all
right getting ready for some heartburn
and get ready for some however you want
to express your excitement so check this
out
seven churches repent seven seals the
progression of evil seven trumpets war
revelation 12 13 and 14 three angels
messages final warning revelation 15 16
17 18 19 the fall or destruction of the
wicked revelation 20 Satan is cast out
revelation 21 and 22 happily ever after
listen to these guys the message for the
seven churches are messages to the seven
angels so just think about this for a
moment their messages to angels when we
think about angels we typically don't
think of leaders of the churches right
what do we think of we think of God's
angels so here's my question to you can
you find do you think that there's a
parallel right the Eugene one Church did
not go through repentance right
absolutely that's the Church of
Philadelphia right but the overall theme
for the churches is repent to the angels
of the churches is repent and ask a
question was there a message given to
angeling in heaven to repent what do you
think let me see your answers I should
see a whole bunch of yeses coming up
right should see a whole bunch of yeses
all right I'm sure yes is all coming the
seven churches right now take us up
you're probably thinking yeah that's
right angels in heaven were called to
repent now watch this the first church
is the Church of Ephesus who can tell me
what was God's appeal to the first
church the problem with the first church
was that while the first church started
out perfect right
anybody screaming yet while the First
Church started out perfect the first
church ended up losing its first love
and it fell so now I could ask you a
question do you see a parallel between
Lucifer's fall in heaven how Lucifer and
the angels started out perfect and then
fell or lost their first love okay if
you see that parallel if you see that
parallel here's what absolutely here's
what I want you to see I want you to
imagine that the seven churches right
parallel God's call for repentance to
the angels in heaven just as Lucifer
started out perfect but lost his first
love I want you to see I want you to
imagine that his appeal to these seven
churches or seven angels of the seven
churches right would parallel the call
to repent for angels in heaven okay so
that's the seven churches hopefully that
sticks in your mind okay yeah the seven
churches is a call for the churches to
repent
just as God did the same thing in heaven
where he called angels who lost their
first love to repent and turn from their
ways now another question was there a
progression of evil in heaven yes I like
that Danny pride forbade them to repent
all right watch this was there a
progression of evil in heaven yeah you
know the answer to that right absolutely
just as the seven seals show this
progression of evil right on earth was
there a progression of evil in heaven
and the answer is absolutely yes so now
we can see that the seven churches
parallel God's call for attendance in
heaven we can also see that the sentence
deals with parallel now I'm not saying
parallel exactly right I'm simply saying
as a shallow right this is a mechanism
to help you juice down the book of
Revelation right so just as there was a
ARP progression of evil right through
the seven seals on earth there was a
progression of evil in heaven absolutely
okay now the seven trumpets what do we
say the seven trumpets represent right
the fame of the seven trumpets was one
war so let me ask you a question
was there war in heaven
absolutely you got it there was war in
heaven yes Carlos they were given a time
of probation so that progression of evil
would explain that absolutely so now
just as right then just as are the seven
trumpets denote war in heaven
oh I'm sorry did no war on earth so we
know there was a parallel because there
was war in heaven all right Donna oh wow
I get it I am so glad you're getting it
and dead exactly it's like a parallel
universe right what comes next
seven seven seals on seven churches to
call to repent seven seals the
progression of evil seven trumpets war
what comes next
the three angels messages correct
revelation 12 13 14 revolve around the
great controversy theme now what are the
three angels messages fear God and give
glory to him Babylon has fallen and if
any man worship the beast or his image
right so not just think there might be a
parallel do you think that there might
be a parrot Evelyn let's just be silent
together for a moment because silence is
the new excitement that's right okay
so just as so the the the
three angels messages was the final is
the final message of mercy is that right
was there a final message of mercy in
heaven right was there a call for angels
to fear God and give glory to him was
there a revelation of who Satan is that
Satan had fought and that Satan was in
total rebellion was there a dividing
line that was strong for angels right
Nicole ooh is right
was there a dividing line that was drawn
for angels if anyone worships Satan
something bad is gonna happen right so
what you have is this parallel from the
seven seals I'm seven churches seven
seals seven trumpets all the way down to
Revelation chapter 12 13 14 the final
message of mercy now now this is the
crazy part right cuz you tell me now
I'm not gonna say anything you tell me
about Revelation 15 16 17 18 and 19 what
is that oh and 20 what is that gonna
parallel let me wait for the answer here
I want you to tell me right because now
you are teaching me so tell me
Revelation 15 16 17 18 19 and 20
you remember what those are about Josh
our judgement exactly the the events may
not be exact but the principles are the
same right exactly
it's almost as as as as if God is saying
to us as it was on earth so it was in
heaven
alright so someone tell me revelation 15
16 17 18 19 what is that that's right
it's the fall absolutely it's Satan
remember revelation 15 16 the plagues 17
18 19 the fall of Babylon 20 Lucifer
cast out so watch this was there war in
heaven did where Lucifer Lucifer where
Lucifer and his angels cast out into an
abyss
absolutely just like revelation 20 where
Lucifer himself is cast out into one of
this as it is it shall be on earth so it
was in heaven all right are you seeing
this are you getting excited yet because
that's that's the whole goal of this
right it's to show you that you can
understand the book of Revelation right
well somebody's putting up a mad face I
hope you're just mad because maybe anger
is a new excitement but it really should
be silenced as a new excitement or you
can just go ahead and just be like
excited right let's check this out guys
what comes in Revelation 21 and 22 what
is it
happily ever after right let me ask you
a question when Satan is cast out of
heaven heaven returns to a state of
peace so basically what we've just done
is we've just taken the entire book of
Revelation and we have imprinted it on
your memory by simply looking at it from
a different perspective right the same
book that we're that you know many of us
were just like oh boy it's hard for me
to remember or oh you know I can't
really I you know I'm not sure if I
understand now
now I'm looking at your responses amen
now you can remember the entire book of
Revelation right the big picture
just by remembering this God called
angels to repent there was a progression
of evil because God is merciful there
then war broke out there was a final
warning giving fear God and give glory
to him and if anyone go it's you know go
with Satan like
there was war in heaven Satan and his
angels were cast out into an abyss and
heaven was once again heaven all right
juice dick right so yes Satan is now
banned from heaven but remember we're
looking at this from an aspect of before
this earth was created in other words
what we're seeing here is that the book
of Revelation in a sense mirrors the
great controversy that happened in
heaven
all right does that make sense it should
you should be able to see this very
clearly and once you get that once you
can lock that into your mind you have
just you just shrunk the book of
Revelation that book that looked like a
huge forest how in the world we're gonna
figure out all these trees all of a
sudden now you're like oh wait a minute
I get this now right and the beautiful
thing about it is that now you can begin
to walk around the forest and do the
same thing from different perspectives
right once you are able to simplify it
from one perspective you have just taken
the bite out of the book of Revelation
right you've consolidated consolidated
it dollar yes you're seeing a pattern of
how God works right and now there's
carefully now when it's time to go when
it's time to go look at the book of I'm
sorry look at the seven churches elder
not welcome when it's time to look at
the seven churches when it's time to
look at the seven seals when it's time
to look at the seven trumpets what you
can do
or what happens is now you can
understand the seven trumpets or the
seven seals or the seven churches
against the backdrop of what happened in
heaven right because now you have a
context that you can use to help you
better understand the book of Revelation
all right so Danny is saying this is why
it's so important for us to reveal
Christ's character through the trials
were going through with an assurance
seat who thought Christ's character was
weak and that he would overcome Christ
with strength you soon realized overcome
evil with good absolutely check this out
we can we can study the entire
controversy just from the events that
took place in heaven and and when we see
the events taking place in heaven when
we see these events and realize that
they are parallel events right to what
happens on earth now we begin now we can
begin to see wow this is why this is how
angels in heaven were deceived right
they were deceived in heaven for some of
the same reasons why people are being
deceived on earth now so we begin to see
the book of Revelation and understand
that it is in one sense it parallels
events that happened in heaven God is
saying to us don't make the same
mistakes than Lucifer and his angels
made in heaven all right okay so that is
one aspect of the book of Revelation now
I spent way more time then I plan to on
that because I have two more things I
need to share with you and I don't know
if I should go ahead and share or if I
should cut it off because I know that
we've been enough for how long how long
have we been on this thing now yeah I'm
not sure how long would be not but you
know what some of you may need to go and
that's okay because this video is being
recorded so
you will be able to go back and look
through it again but if it's okay let me
go on and share see if I can share one
of these other points I wanted to share
and yeah okay
so let's let's do this all right
thirty-eight minutes all right I'm gonna
try to really just this down really
really juice this down okay
and I'm gonna stick one so this is
crucial to understand and you guys see
if you can help me with this okay so the
book of Revelation is definitely written
on a pattern and hopefully I've just
demonstrated that right we just saw yeah
seven churches seven seals seven
trumpets revelation 12 13 14 and then
revelation 15 through 20 and then
revelation 21 and 22 parallel the great
controversy in heaven okay but that's
not the only pattern because there are
two other patterns that are crucial to
understand if you want to rightly
understand the book of Revelation now
let me share this there are a lot of
people that teach on the book of
Revelation and I believe that without
teaching the revelation in the context
of these two patterns you can end up
going off on things that may seem to be
right but are wrong right wrong right
well you get what I'm saying
think of it like this how many different
interpretations have you heard of the
seven trumpets how many different
seven kings how many different
interpretations have you heard of the
seven seals okay yeah there are a lot of
people that are you know there's a lot
of different interpretations out there
and it's you know it's daunting because
as we hear these different
interpretations we you know we kind of
connect
with some preachers better than me
connect with others some teachers but it
better than we connect with others but
when we hear these different
interpretations we kind of on left
wondering man you know it does anyone
have it right because like you know this
person over here says no the seven
trumpets our future this person says no
the seven trumpets have to do with the
fall of the Roman Empire in four
different divisions this person says the
seven churches you know happen over
progression of time so how do we know
which of these is the right you and for
me right the way that I have approached
the book of Revelation is that the book
of Revelation has to be based on a
pattern it is not based on a pattern
then I can choose whatever I want to
choose and you know say okay this means
this and this means that but if I have a
pattern that I know that whatever falls
outside of the pattern cannot be the
right interpretation you know of the
thing I'm looking at does that make
sense all right hopefully that makes
sense so let me share with you the two
patterns that the book of Revelation is
written on the first pattern is the
pattern of the sanctuary and the second
pattern is the pattern of the feast days
now let me do the feast a pattern first
because I want you to see this is
absolutely like mind-blowing okay so I'm
just gonna do this you know just follow
me and I want you to see if you can help
me out here so there are seven feast
days in the Bible all right and can you
guys tell me what those feasts are
there's the feast of what's the first
feast is the Passover is that right okay
thumbs up if you got that Passover
excellent all right you gotta call it a
Passover the second feast is a feast of
unleavened bread and the third feast is
the feast of firstfruits right those
three feasts occurred
together Passover unleavened bread
firstfruits now
we know that those three feasts point to
the death burial and resurrection of
Jesus Christ all right very good
the next feast was 50 days later and
that was a feast of Pentecost and these
feasts occurred in the beginning of the
Jewish year now the feasts that occurred
toward the end of the Jewish year were
the Feast of Trumpets and then the feast
of I'm sorry the Day of Atonement right
and then the final feast was the Feast
of Tabernacles right and that's where
the Jews celebrated because the Day of
Atonement had passed that they have
judgment had passed and the Feast of
Tabernacles was a celebration okay so
here the feasts again right the feast of
[Music]
Passover and then unleavened bread and
then firstfruits okay followed by
Pentecost and then and then Feast of
Trumpets followed by the Day of
Atonement and then the last one was the
Feast of Tabernacles right and this is
what made up the Jewish year these were
made of the Jewish year so when Jesus
comes on the scene okay he makes his
pronouncement and he says in the book of
Matthew I believe it is that after his
baptism right he goes into the temple
and he preaches and he says this
statement he says that be acceptable he
has come to preach the Spirit of the
Lord is upon me because he has anointed
me to preach the gospel to the poor dah
dah dah and then he says to preach the
acceptable year of the Lord the
acceptable year of the Lord so what does
that mean the acceptable year of the
Lord okay this is this is Cru
to understand alright don't feel like a
pastime lost now you're not lost you're
not lost okay
trust me check this out when God called
the children of Israel out of Egypt he
told them that the Passover was to be
the beginning of months for them right
this was to be the beginning of their
year so every year they went through
this same cycle Passover unleavened
bread first fruits followed by Feast of
Tabernacles and then later in the year
trumpets damned atonement Tabernacles
every year they went through the same
process it was a it was a year that had
gospel significance right and the gospel
significance was the plan of salvation
because those seven feasts explained the
plan of salvation now now watch this
when Jesus comes on the scene he
basically says hey I'm here to preach
the acceptable year of the Lord what is
the acceptable year of the Lord what
does he mean the year of the Lord well
it goes back to the Old Testament that
prophetic year that God implemented
right in the book of Exodus so how did
the year begin it began with the
Passover all right
so watch this when Jesus comes on the
scene just before John the Baptist had
pointed to him at the Jordan and said
behold the lamb of God which takes away
the sin of the world
well the Lamb of God is the Passover
lamb that Passover lamb came to start
the acceptable year of the Lord and what
I'm suggesting to you is that the entire
New Testament is the acceptable year of
the Lord
culminating with the book of Revelation
let me explain and get ready for some
heartburn get ready for some excitement
because watch this Matthew Mark Luke and
John they all
all around what the death what else
burial what else resurrection of Jesus
Christ right so in other words we might
say Matthew Mark Luke and John parallel
Passover unleavened bread and first
fruits all right if you get that just
give me a thumbs up give me a heart let
me see something I want to make sure
that you you got that just now Matthew
Mark Luke and John all revolve around
the death Passover burial unleavened
bread resurrection firstfruits of Jesus
Christ okay
it's very good all right excellent
now what comes after the feast of
firstfruits let me see if you can give
me the answer right here right Danny I
think you're getting this what comes
after the feast of firstfruits after the
feast of firstfruits you have the feast
of Pentecost what book comes after
Matthew Mark Luke and John
absolutely the feast of Pentecost
parallels the book of Acts all right I
think you guys are catching this right
the book of Pentecost parallels the book
of Acts and really Pentecost was about
the multiplying right of God's people
write this book of it that's they've
kind of cost three thousand baptized and
then these firstfruits just keep growing
in the church right so if you look at
the book of Acts and then go through the
entire New Testament right Romans and
and the epistles all of those books are
talking about the growth of the early
church right or talking about the the
way the early church grew and they're
you know being founded on the Word of
God and on prayer and and how the
churches grew and prospered
that's right Leon stop the madness right
it looks like you guys are getting this
all right now now the next
East is the trumpets and the trumpets
were about warnings and guess what when
you get to the book of Revelation so
look we've just done right Matthew Mark
Luke and John Passover unleavened bread
firstfruits the book of Acts all the way
through the all the epistles of the in
Testament parallels Pentecost right the
growth of the early church
now comes revelation and in the book of
Revelation here's what you have the book
begins with warnings to repent
Revelation chapter 1 all the way through
chapter 11 parallel the trumpets I'm not
talking about the prophetic trumpets
right I'm talking not talking about the
seven trumpets in Revelation I'm talking
about the the Feast of Trumpets right
the warning and by the way the Feast of
Trumpets were to warn that the day of
atonement was coming that was the
purpose of the trumpets right so when
you look at the seven churches the seven
seals and the seven trumpets they are in
essence given to us to prepare us
remember tip us up revelation 1 to 11 is
the first half of the book of Revelation
man I'm just getting too excited about
this Revelation chapter 1 to 11 is the
first half of the book of Revelation
revelation 12 to 22 is the last half
revelation 1 to 11 all unfolds there
it's all about warning right shake the
sound dance in revelation 11 and verse
17 for the first time in the book of
Revelation you have the most holy place
opening up this is where John says that
the seventh trumpet sounded and they and
there was he says uh he looked and saw
that Temple of the tabernacle of the
testimony in heaven was opened and they
were seeing the arc of his Testament
that is John
spiritually symbolically bringing us
into the most holy place in the book of
Revelation and remember what is the most
holy place parallel what feast does it
parallel it parallels the Day of
Atonement right so listen carefully
Matthew Mark Luke and John Passover
unleavened bread fresh fruits the book
of Acts let me get some water here click
into it sack baby the book of Acts I'll
calm down I'm trying to calm down the
book of Acts there you go thank you
Josh you put the verse at there's
revelation 11 verse 19 so the book of
Acts Pentecost all the way through to
Jude it's all talking about the early
church the growth of the early church
the multiplication of the early church
because the early church was following
the pure gospel when we get to
revelation 11 we now move into warnings
rather I'm sorry Revelation chapter 1 we
now move into warnings those warnings
Revelation chapter 1 all the way to
through chapter 11 7 churches the seven
seals the seven trumpets are warning us
that something is coming and what is
that something
revelation chapter 11 verse 19 the most
holy place is open which brings us to
the day of a king so revelation 12 13
and 14 are all focused around the Day of
Atonement and that's why we as
Adventists are always preaching about
Revelation 12 13 and 14 right the three
angels messages fear God and give glory
and for that our judgment has come the
beast from the sea and the beast from
the earth revelation 12 he went to make
war with the remnant of her seed which
keep the commandments of God and have
the testimony of Jesus absolutely Carlos
you got it you've already jumped ahead
of me right you're already seeing this
so check this out
revelation 12 13 and 14 day of atonement
now this is the crazy thing right
because I need you to help me on this
in Revelation chapter what happened at
the end of the Day of Atonement right if
you look at the video 16 I think it's 23
at the closing of the Day of Atonement
more water at the closing of the Day of
Atonement the high priest came out of
the temple those who had not
participated in the Day of Atonement
were cut off and the high priests
laid his hands on the head of the
scapegoat and sends him out into a
desolate place
do not let me yell all by myself up in
this place right now at the close of the
Day of Atonement the wicked are cut off
and sin is put on the head of the
scapegoat who was sent out into a
desolate place question for you can
someone tell tell me what happens in
Revelation chapter 15 and chapter 16
what happens there hmm I know
[Music]
you got it closed approbation the
plagues are poured out upon the wicked
Babylon is fallen and Jesus who has just
stepped out of the most holy place lays
hands on when the Bible says he laid
hold on on the dragon the term literally
means laid hands on what did the high
priest do at the end of the Day of
Atonement yes Judy yell you know yell
because that's what you need to do right
now the end of the Day of Atonement the
high priest laid hands on the head of
the scapegoat what does Jesus do in
Revelation chapter 20 he lays hands on
the head of the scapegoat and sends him
out into a desolate place alright now
when that is over what was the next
feast it was a feast of what what oh I
can't hear you what oh yeah that's right
the feast of tabernacles
how does revelation 21 and 22 put it
behold the what the tabernacle of God is
with men it is that feasts of the people
celebrated because the year was over
they do you see what we just did the
entire New Testament is the acceptable
year of the Lord
it begins with Passover unleavened bread
firstfruits continues on with Pentecost
brings the warning with the trumpets
brings us into the Day of Atonement
shows us what happens at the end of the
Day of Atonement and then the tabernacle
of God is with men okay are you catching
this here's what we've just done and I'm
sorry this but I I don't have time to
give you the last parallel which is the
sanctuary because we'll be on here for
another long time and many of you need
to go to sleep because we have work
tomorrow or something important that you
need to do and I don't want to keep you
here for another 20 or 30 minutes or so
but let's do this let me summarize this
what we've just done is we've just
juiced the book of Revelation excuse me
in two different contexts right one in
heaven rung on the feast days and
there's a third one the sanctuary so
we're not gonna be able to cover that
tonight but I want you to see that what
we've just done will probably help you
like just think about this if you go
through this in your mind like 10 more
times or over tonight you will probably
get up tomorrow morning and we'll have
the book of Revelation locked into your
mind like you never had before you catch
that like if you just said the Pioneers
studied all night let's do it that is
funny well it's not funny it's powerful
yeah but I asked some other things I
need to do tonight as well
got more stuff to accomplish here but
this is what's going on guys if you just
in your mind say okay what do we just do
okay we just saw seven churches God
warned Satan to repent seven seals the
progression of evil in Heaven's
trumpets war in heaven revelation 12 13
14 the final warning of message given to
Satan in heaven revelation 15 to 20
Satan cast out of heaven and his angels
revelation 21 and 22 heaven in peace
again wow I just got the book of
Revelation juice I don't know though I
don't really get all the trees yet but I
understand the forest now I see it okay
or we can just go with the feast days
Matthew Mark Luke and John Passover
unleavened bread firstfruits the book of
Acts Pentecost all the way through to
Jude Revelation chapters 1 to 11 the
trumpets the warnings preparing us for
Revelation chapter 12 13 and 14 the day
of atonement at the end of which
chapters 15 through 20 the wicked are
cut off and Satan is cast out into a
desolate place revelation 21 and 22 the
Feast of Tabernacles right you see how
quickly I just did that I have no notes
in front of me that means I just did
this all from memory and guess what ask
my wife how good my memory is and she
will tell you it is horrible so I have a
horrible memory horrible but a picture
is worth a thousand words and when you
see stuff in pictures suddenly that
really really really bad memory you have
begins to not be so bad
all right so I'm Nita
how are you it is good to see you on
here alright so man we've grown to 79
viewers right now this is this is good I
know that I said I was going to do the
trumpets and I'm sorry the sanctuary
parallel
[Music]
I can give that to you in like two
minutes
I'm not gonna be able to explain it in
detail but I'll give it to you in two
minutes
is that okay and then you can go to
sleep if you are able to sleep tonight
okay
same pattern there are six articles of
furniture in the sanctuary
there's the altar of sacrifice in the
outer court there's the Laver in the
outer Court this is followed by the
table of showbread altar of incense and
seven-branch candlestick in the holy
place followed by the most holy place so
very simple the altar of sacrifice
represents the sacrifice of Christ right
Matthew Mark Luke and John what do they
cover the altar of sacrifice so Matthew
Mark Luke and John parallel the altar of
sacrifice in the outer court what comes
next the Laver rolls the Laver about
baptism what is the next book after
Matthew Mark Luke and John are you
getting excited again the next book is
Pentecost which has to do with what
baptism the outpouring of the Holy
Spirit yeah so if you take that
outpouring of the Holy Spirit baptism
and take that all the way through right
to the book of Jude just like we did
with the seventh the feast days we're
gonna do with the sanctuary so the altar
I'm sorry the Laver the Laver parallels
the purification of God's church right
baptism the growth of God's church and
that's we go from Romans all the way
through to Jude again it's it's the
history of the church as it grows
because the church is following the pure
gospel now when we get to the book of
Revelation what do we have we have the
seven churches but the seven churches
unfold within the count there's an
opening vision for the seven churches
and the opening vision is Jesus
standing in the middle of seven golden
candlesticks
so the seven churches lets us know that
we have now moved from the outer court
right so Matthew Mark Luke and John
outer court Romans all the way to Jude
out of court
revelations seven churches brings us
into the holy place the seven churches
unfold with Jesus in the midst of the
seven golden candlesticks the seven
seals unfold within the context of the
table of showbread now I'm gonna give
the street very quickly because this
could be a little bit complicated but
it's not don't don't think that it's not
complicated there's a throne that is
seen in Revelation chapter four and five
that throne is right is directly across
from the seven-branched candlestick
there was only one article of furniture
in the seven branch directly across from
the seven-branched candlestick and that
was a table of showbread the table of
showbread is located on the sides of the
north in the sanctuary god's throne
according to Psalm 48 verse wanted to is
on the sides of the north so what we
know is that the seven seals unfolds
within the context of the table of
showbread
right so seven churches seven-branch
candlestick seven seals table of
showbread the seven trumpets unfold
within the context of guess what
where does John see the angel he sees
them standing by the altar of incense so
check us out guys seven seals seven
trumpets seven churches all unfold
within the context of the holy place and
here's something that you need to
understand that is crucial in the Old
Testament the priests ministered
simultaneously at the altar of incense
the table of showbread and the
seven-branched candlestick it was a
simultaneous ministry what does that
tell us here's what it tells us the
seven churches seven seals and seven
trumpets must unfold simultaneous
it's not one after the other the seven
churches and then the seven seals and
then the seven trumpets are yet future
no we follow the pattern of the Old
Testament which says that the priests
ministered at all three simultaneously
so check this out you know that tells us
this is the first Church the first seal
and the first trumpet are gonna parallel
so with the second so with the third all
the way now they're gonna parallel that
helps us to know our interpretation of
the seventh trumpet must match the set
the seventh seal and the seventh Church
the same with the first trumpet it must
match the first seal and the first
Church you get the idea that's how we
get to check our work to see hey am i
interpreting this right okay finally
revelation 11 what do we see happening
we see the 7 we see the most holy place
opening up in revelation 11 verse 19
which means that from revelation 11 19
we are now brought into the most holy
place right so from revelation 11 19 all
the way to Revelation chapter 20 it's
all most holy place Ark of the Covenant
theme revelation 21 and 22 again the
tabernacle of God is with men so what
have we just done we've just seen that
Matthew Mark Luke and John paralleled
the altar sacrifice acts all the way
through to Jude parallels the Laver and
then seven churches seven seals seven
trumpets parallel altar of seven-branch
candlestick table of showbread altar of
incense and then from revelation 11 17
the latter half of the book brings us
into the most holy place and thus we see
that the entire book of Revelation is
written on a pattern they
is how you put the puzzle together this
is how you bring these pictures together
this is why when you study the Bible
using pictures photo theology right when
you study the Bible using pictures it
changes everything
right this is going to be specifically
for those of you who are saying yeah I
want to learn how to teach the book of
Revelation so what I'm gonna put in the
link and I don't know it may be in the
link already is a two month course that
I have on the book of Revelation and
during that - on the course we're gonna
be doing just like we did tonight but
we're gonna be doing it in a more it's
going to be more question-and-answer as
you go through this course so I'm gonna
be teaching you how to teach not how to
understand about how to teach the book
of Revelation because there isn't if you
can teach it game over right if you can
teach it I believe that God that that's
what God has all Timothy calling us to
do right we've got to know this so well
that we're able to teach